<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on productivity</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/</link><description>Recent content on Thoughts on productivity</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022 Cornelius Schumacher</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 22:46:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cornelius.github.io/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mochary Method Curriculum</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/mochary-method/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 22:46:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/mochary-method/</guid><description>Thoughts on productivity https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/mochary-method/ -&lt;p>Matt Mochary is a business coach who has coached a lot of big names in the tech space, startups, investement firms. He openly shares his method, which is a collection of a lot of great tactical advice, put together from all kind of sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His target audience are CEOs, but the method contains a lot of elements which are useful in different roles as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read on the big collection as a Google Document with plenty to material and references: &lt;a href="https://t.co/A8J51IzYhz">Mochary Method Curriculum&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the core pieces is &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1sDWHUm6zwEGiPBQH2Ig6DDvVL-IEQSlfNeQnR2mhjmE/edit">fear and anger&lt;/a>, how they give bad advice and how to get out of this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another core piece is &amp;ldquo;Top Goal&amp;rdquo;, reserving time for working on your own top priority, not letting outside requests eat up all of your time. In a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/bCel0X2Ta7U">Lenny&amp;rsquo;s Podcast&lt;/a> he shared that he is doing this himself with an accountability partner, which forces him to focus. You could do this with the support of an app, such as &lt;a href="https://www.getsupporti.com/">Supporti&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot more, what you will already know, such as Inbox Zero, Getting Things Done, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I found particular interesting is the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HmaRdtk8R5GQtMj72Y6XhHTru5SQAiiqDfDP3qy73k4/edit">Energy Audit&lt;/a>. By identifying what activities bring you energy and getting rid of activities which lower your energy you get to work in the &amp;ldquo;genius zone&amp;rdquo;. This is where you work on things you truly enjoy and where you are truly excellent. According to Matt magic happens there.&lt;/p>
- https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/mochary-method/ - 2022 Cornelius Schumacher</description></item><item><title>Philosophy</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:51:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/philosophy/</guid><description>Thoughts on productivity https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/philosophy/ -&lt;p>It can play a role how you approach productivity, with what mindset you look at it, what mental models you build and use to think about it. This is what I would call the philosophy of productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="todos">Todos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One example is how you look at a &lt;strong>to do&lt;/strong> list. It can be tasks ahead, such as &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;feed the penguins&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. You could also look at it as a &lt;strong>done&lt;/strong> list, and formulate your todos from the perspective of their results, such as &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;the penguins are well fed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. Or you you take another perspective and define a &lt;strong>not to do&lt;/strong> list, which keeps you away from distractions, such as &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t feed the seals&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also like the notion of &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;todo bankruptcy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>. Todos tend to accumulate. There seems to be an inherent natural law that todo list always grow bigger over time up to a point where you can&amp;rsquo;t possibly even think of getting everything done on the list. Giving up on the list, declaring todo bankruptcy and start fresh is one strategy how to deal with it. An elegant way is to switch &lt;a href="./top/posts/tools/">tools&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="busyness">Busyness&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you want to get something done, ask a busy person to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I always was fascinated by the truth in this saying. It’s such a great example of unintuitive but insightful wisdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two angles I like about it in particular:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is the beauty of constraints it expresses. If you are busy, if you are limited in time, you need to use your time well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second is the learning it implies. Doing things keeps you busy, and from doing things you learn. One of the things you learn is how to do more.&lt;/p>
- https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/philosophy/ - 2022 Cornelius Schumacher</description></item><item><title>Protocols</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/protocols/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:34:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/protocols/</guid><description>Thoughts on productivity https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/protocols/ -&lt;p>How can you modify your behavior to be more productive? How can you create an environment which gets you done more? What psycholgiccal effects can you utilize to achieve more? It boils down to the question: &lt;strong>What are the protocols you can follow to increase productivity?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="focus">Focus&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the factors which has the biggest impact on productivity is focus. If you direct your energy on one target, success can feel effortless.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dragon-day">Dragon Day&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the most interesting protocols I have experimented with is the Dragon Day. It creates an extremly strongly focusing enviroment to get work done on one day with 10 hours of work and 4 hours of breaks. It mixes exercises for the body and the mind, and can have amazing results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="developer-sprints">Developer Sprints&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Another approach is what we in KDE call developer sprints. Hackathons are a variant of it. These are software development oriented, but the concept also has been adapted for example for book sprints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written about how I experienced developer sprints on my blog:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2014/08/running-on-cheese-and-chocolate_26.html">Running on cheese and chocolate&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.cornelius-schumacher.de/2010/01/anatomy-of-developer-sprint.html">Anatomy of a developer sprint&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="clear-mind">Clear mind&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When reading about the Getting Things Done method, the thing which resonated most with me was the &amp;ldquo;sweeping your mind&amp;rdquo; practice, i.e. writing everything down what is on your mind and putting it in the system, so that you never have to worry about forgetting something or missing something. If this works it gets you a clear mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another interesting perspective I found in the book &amp;ldquo;When it gets crazy at work&amp;rdquo;. After reading it I would say the real title of the book is &amp;ldquo;Choose calm&amp;rdquo;. It contains a lot of thoughts about how to be productive without giving in to the crazyness of work.&lt;/p>
- https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/protocols/ - 2022 Cornelius Schumacher</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:22:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/tools/</guid><description>Thoughts on productivity https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/tools/ -&lt;p>Productivity has some different aspects. One of them is tools. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of the industrial perspective. Use the right tools and you will get more done. Improve your tools and your productivity will increase.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“If I only had an hour to chop down a tree, I would spend the first 45 minutes sharpening my axe.” – Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For personal productivity, especially for intellectual work, a lot of tools are software tools. There is a whole class of productivity software. It is related to personal information management or knowledge management. All can help you to get more efficient with your mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have worked on a number of tools which I would put into the productivity software category.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with &lt;a href="https://apps.kde.org/korganizer/">KOrganizer&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://kde.org">KDE&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s calendar and todo application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the more sophisticated experiments was &lt;a href="https://github.com/cornelius/bliss">Bliss&lt;/a>. I still use it today to organize my work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tool I use for implementing &lt;a href="https://www.personalkanban.com/">Personal Kanban&lt;/a> is &lt;a href="https://trello.com">Trello&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And somehow &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/">git&lt;/a>, often augmented by &lt;a href="https://github.com">GitHub&lt;/a>, is at the center of a lot of these tool-based approaches.&lt;/p>
- https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/tools/ - 2022 Cornelius Schumacher</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Productivity</title><link>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 17:18:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/</guid><description>Thoughts on productivity https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/ -&lt;p>This site collects some thoughts about productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-think-about-productivity">Why think about productivity?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We all have limited time and energy. How to put this to good use is a question which is relevant to most people. If you have ideas, ambitions, goals, dreams, you will have to be mindful about how you go about them in order to achieve what you want to achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It probably is dependent on your personality how much you want to think about productivity. I&amp;rsquo;m for example an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enneagram_of_Personality">Enneagram Type Three&lt;/a>, nick-named the &amp;ldquo;achiever&amp;rdquo;. Productivity often is on my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-productivity">What is productivity?&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Productivity is the efficiency of production of goods or services expressed by some measure. Measurements of productivity are often expressed as a ratio of an aggregate output to a single input or an aggregate input used in a production process, i.e. output per unit of input, typically over a specific period of time. &amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Productivity">Wikipedia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Here we are taking a less economic and a more personal perspective. We are thinking about personal production of the things we create as part of our life. This might be goods and services, but it also could be ideas, thoughts, chores, art, craft, maybe it can even be applied to things such as relationships, emotions, fun.&lt;/p>
- https://cornelius.github.io/top/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/ - 2022 Cornelius Schumacher</description></item></channel></rss>