<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Thoughts on productivity</title><link>http://example.org/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Thoughts on productivity</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022 Cornelius Schumacher</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:51:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Philosophy</title><link>http://example.org/posts/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:51:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/philosophy/</guid><description>It can play a role how you approach productivity, with what mindset you look at it, what mental models you build and use to think about it. This is what I would call the philosophy of productivity.
Todos One example is how you look at a to do list. It can be tasks ahead, such as &amp;ldquo;feed the penguins&amp;rdquo;. You could also look at it as a done list, and formulate your todos from the perspective of their results, such as &amp;ldquo;the penguins are well fed&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Protocols</title><link>http://example.org/posts/protocols/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:34:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/protocols/</guid><description>How can you modify your behavior to be more productive? How can you create an environment which gets you done more? What psycholgiccal effects can you utilize to achieve more? It boils down to the question: What are the protocols you can follow to increase productivity?
Focus One of the factors which has the biggest impact on productivity is focus. If you direct your energy on one target, success can feel effortless.</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>http://example.org/posts/tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 18:22:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/tools/</guid><description>Productivity has some different aspects. One of them is tools. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of the industrial perspective. Use the right tools and you will get more done. Improve your tools and your productivity will increase.
“If I only had an hour to chop down a tree, I would spend the first 45 minutes sharpening my axe.” – Abraham Lincoln.
For personal productivity, especially for intellectual work, a lot of tools are software tools.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Productivity</title><link>http://example.org/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 17:18:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/thoughts-on-productivity/</guid><description>This site collects some thoughts about productivity.
Why think about productivity? We all have limited time and energy. How to put this to good use is a question which is relevant to most people. If you have ideas, ambitions, goals, dreams, you will have to be mindful about how you go about them in order to achieve what you want to achieve.
It probably is dependent on your personality how much you want to think about productivity.</description></item></channel></rss>